

University of Wisconsin-Madison Computer Sciences Department 1210 W Dayton St, Madison, WI 53726 USA dporfirio@wisc.edu http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~dporfirio/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in making the process of programming social robots easy and approachable for experts and non-expert designers alike. My work spans using **formal verification** to assist designers reason about interaction social norms, **program synthesis** to assist designers in implementing these interactions, and using **program repair** to automatically fix these interactions.

EDUCATION

PhD University of Wisconsin–Madison (UW–Madison), Madison, WI, USA Computer Sciences

MSc UW–Madison, Madison, WI, USA 2016-2018 Computer Sciences

BS University of Arizona (UA), Tucson, AZ, USA 2011-2016 Double degree (hon) in computer science and physiology Minor in mathematics Summa cum laude

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Doctoral Research 2016-present

UW-Madison, Madison, WI, USA

Computer Sciences

Advisors: Drs. Bilge Mutlu, Aws Albarghouthi, and Allison Sauppé

Undergraduate Senior Thesis 2015-2016

UW-Madison, Madison, WI, USA

Computer Sciences

Advisor: Dr. John Kececioglu

Undergraduate Research 2013-2014

UW-Madison, Madison, WI, USA

Computer Sciences

Advisors: Drs. E. Fiona Bailey and Joanna Masel

FELLOWSHIPS, HONORS, and AWARDS

Heidelberg Laureate Forum Invited to attend as a young researcher	2019
Best Paper Award UIST '18	2018
NSF Graduate Research Fellowship	2017
Advanced Opportunity Fellowship Selected by the UW–Madison Computer Sciences Department	2016
Excellence in Undergraduate Research Award Selected by the UA Department of Computer Science	2016
Galileo Circle Scholar Selected by the UA Department of Computer Science	2015
National Hispanic Scholar Selected by the National Hispanic Recognition Program	2011

Awarded during six semesters at UA

PUBLICATIONS

Porfirio, D., Fisher, E., Sauppé, A., Albarghouthi, A., & Mutlu, B. (2019, October). Bodystorming Human-Robot Interactions. In Proceedings of the 32nd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (pp. 479-491). ACM.

Porfirio, D., Sauppé, A., Albarghouthi, A., & Mutlu, B. (2019, March). Computational Tools for Human-Robot Interaction Design. In 2019 14th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI) (pp. 733-735). IEEE.

Porfirio, D., Sauppé, A., Albarghouthi, A., & Mutlu, B. (2018, October). Authoring and verifying human-robot interactions. In The 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (pp. 75-86). ACM.

Xiong, K., McEntee, J. P., **Porfirio, D. J.**, & Masel, J. (2017). Drift barriers to quality control when genes are expressed at different levels. Genetics, 205(1), 397-407.

Shumway, K. R., **Porfirio, D. J.**, & Bailey, E. F. (2015). Phonation-related rate coding and recruitment in the genioglossus muscle. Experimental brain research, 233(7), 2133-2140.

POSTERS

Porfirio, D., Sauppé, A., Albarghouthi, A., & Mutlu, B. (2019) Computational Tools for Human-Robot Interaction Design, ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction; Daegu, South Korea

Porfirio, D., Sauppé, A., Albarghouthi, A., & Mutlu, B. (2017) Construction and Formal Verification of Human-Robot Interaction Designs, The Human Computer Interaction Consortium 2017 Workshop; Pajaro Dunes, CA

Karlie R. Shumway, **David J Porfirio**, E. Fiona Bailey (2014) Force Regulation in cranial and spinal motoneuron pools, 25th Annual Undergraduate Biology Research Conference; Tucson, AZ

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, UA

Summer 2015

Duties: holding office hours and grading programming assignments CSC 352, Systems Programming and Unix

Section Leader, UA Fall 2014 - Spring 2015

Duties: teaching lab sessions, holding office hours, and grading assignments

CSC 245, Introduction to Discrete Structures CSC 227, Program Design and Development

OUTREACH

Grandparents University

2018-present

Instructor

Co-taught social robotics lecture and lab sessions geared towards children and their grandparents.

UA Mortar Board Senior Honor Society

2014-2015

Member

Performed community service and various times during membership.

Tucson Medical Center 2012-2013

Worked over 200 hours in the Pediatrics and Labor and Delivery Departments, assisting nurses and visitors